CLAUDIA PAVA

MARKETING STRATEGIST

Experienced marketing strategist with proven success in offline and online marketing strategies, project management, and achieving measurable results for top organizations. Expertise in brand awareness, social media engagement, lead generation, increasing client conversion rates, and expanding sales channels.

CONTACT INFO



+57 3104489261- Colombia



cjpavad@gmail.com



http://www.linkedin.com /in/claudia-pava-dávila

EDUCATION

MA, MARKETING MANAGEMENT.

Eafit University. Colombia.

BA, INDUSTRIAL DESIGN.

Pontificia Bolivariana University. Colombia.

LEADERSHIP MANAGEMENT.

Incolda, Cesa University. Colombia.

04-2008 - 06-2008. 60hs.

CORE COMPETENCIES

- Offline & Online marketing & growth strategies.
- SEO/SEM.
- Analytics (Google Analytics, Tag Manager).
- Lead generation.

 Paid media platforms & campaigns (Meta, LinkedIn, Google).

LANGUAGES

SPANISH: Native level.

ENGLISH: advanced level. C1

• Brand development & communication.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Director of Marketing - Independent Contractor

NORTHWEST CENTER - (SEATTLE - WA).

Non-profit that promotes the growth, development, and independence of people with disabilities through programs of therapy, education, and work opportunities.

https://www.nwcenter.org/

Feb 2024 - Present | Remote

- Develop marketing campaigns to drive audience action, generating leads and sales opportunities for the organization's seven different businesses.
- Create and execute marketing strategies for new products and services and identify potential markets.
- Actively manage digital properties, including the websites and supervise paid campaigns on Facebook, Instagram, Google, and LinkedIn.
- Analyzed website metrics such as CTR, conversion rates, & promotional effectiveness to refine strategies.
- Administered a US\$1.5M marketing and communications budget and oversee the marketing team.

Director of Marketing - Independent Contractor

DARASH AHAVA FOUNDATION - (PHOENIX - AZ)

Global non-profit focused on emotional healing through art with a unique, sustainable business model.

www.da.foundation

Jan 2023 - Jan 2024 | Remote

- Designed comprehensive digital and offline marketing plans for a startup foundation.
- Set up Google Analytics and improved SEO performance.
- Implemented email marketing campaigns, social media paid campaigns and fundraising strategies.
- Directed a cross-functional team of content developer, web designer, and graphic designer.

Marketing Director

IPF. Ingredients and functional products for the food industry. (Colombia)

www.ipf.com.co

2019 - 2021 | Hybrid

- Established and scaled the marketing department, leading digital transformation initiatives to enhance online visibility.
- Implemented lead generation strategies, delivering over 1,000 qualified leads & establishing and launching the E-commerce channel.
- Execute SEO initiatives and lead content marketing campaigns.
- Directed brand strategy and paid campaigns on Facebook, Instagram, Google, and LinkedIn.

Marketing Director

WEST QUÍMICA. Environmentally friendly/biodegradable cleaning and disinfection solutions. (Colombia).

www.westquimica.com

2018 - 2019 | Hybrid

- Led marketing, communications, customer service, and advertising departments.
- Executed integrated online & offline marketing and communication strategies.
- Directed a team of eight and collaborated with external graphic design agencies.
- Oversaw targeted paid campaigns to strengthen market presence and enhance brand awareness. Facebook, Instagram, Google, and LinkedIn.
- Managed the marketing budget.

Marketing Director

PEGAUCHO. Manufacturing Company. (Colombia)

www.pegaucho.com

2016 - 2018.

- Lead the company's marketing, communications, and customer service departments.
- Launched comprehensive marketing plans and campaigns across digital and offline channels, focusing on brand growth and customer engagement.
- Executed multi-channel campaigns, leveraging SEO/SEM strategies, email marketing, social media and paid platforms.
- Implemented growth-focused initiatives to enhance market presence & lead generation.

Marketing Consultant.

REAL MARKETING. Consultancy firm in strategy, marketing, sales, and customer service. (Colombia).

www.realmercadeo.com

2011 - 2013.

- Provided strategic consulting in marketing, sales, and customer service to different companies.
- Designed and implemented client-specific strategies to enhance customer journeys and drive growth.

Founder and General Manager

LATAMINSIGHT. Marketing agency serving international clients. (Colombia).

2009 - 2015.

- Established a marketing agency catering international clients across diverse industries.
- Developed integrated marketing and communication strategies including market research, digital campaigns, and customer acquisition initiatives for foreign companies entering Latin American markets.

National Trade Marketing Director.

TIGO. By Millicom International, a telecommunications company specializing in mobile phone services. (Colombia).

www.tigo.com.co

2008 - 2009.

- Led national marketing and sales strategies, focusing on expanding sales channels.
- Managed a \$3M marketing budget and achieved measurable improvements in brand positioning and customer acquisition.
- Directed a nationwide rebranding initiative and strategic sponsorship deals with major Colombian sports teams.
- Supervised a team of 13 marketing analysts and collaborated with sales executives to achieve sales budget targets.

Regional Trade Marketing Analyst.

TIGO. By Millicom International, a telecommunications company specializing in mobile phone services. (Colombia)

www.tigo.com.co

2006 - 2008.

- Developed and executed regional trade marketing strategies, ensuring consistent corporate branding across all channels.
- Directed the successful rebranding of the former brand Ola to Tigo within the region.
- Designed sales strategies to enhance market positioning and strengthen the sub-distributor network.
- Collaborated with the regional director and sales team to achieve sales budget targets.
- Managed the regional marketing budget, optimizing for ROI and measurable outcomes.

CERTIFICATIONS

- Google Ads Certified January 2022.
- Facebook Ads (Meta Blueprint) Certified July 2021.
- SEO Fundamentals October 2021.
- Scrum Foundation Professional Certificate (SFPC) August 2022.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Digital Advertising: Google Ads, Meta Ads Manager, LinkedIn Campaign Manager, LinkedIn Sale Navigator.
- Data Analytics: Google Analytics, Tag Manager, Data Visualization Tools, Power Bl.
- Marketing Automation: CRM Dynamic & HubSpot.
- Email Marketing Tools: Mailchimp, Constant Contact, HubSpot, Uplead.
- Project Management: Agile (Scrum), Budget Planning.
- Al Tools: Jasper, ChatGPT & Copilot.
- Creative Tools: Canva

SOFT SKILLS

- Leadership
- · Accountability.
- · Adaptability.
- Teamwork.
- Critical thinking and problem-solving.
- Organization
- Creativity.
- Clear communication.
- Decisiveness.